Name: Julius Njeru Thuo

Email: juliusn411@gmail.com
Phone number: +254768585724

Nationality: **Kenyan** 

Membership in Professional Societies: The Andela Learning community, Huawei ICT Academy.

# **Professional summary**

I am an entry level software engineer with expertise in Web application development. I am a passionate and talented young graduate who enjoys the art of creating python applications using Django. With Django, I have created several web applications which I mostly used to learn the core fundamentals of the framework such as CRUD operations, search engine optimization (SEO) techniques, building of models and database schema and building of APIs by serializing models. I have also used the framework to build backend solutions for my clients on Fiverr, giving me invaluable experience in using the framework commercially.

### **Key Qualifications**

- Proficient Python programming language skills.
- ◆ Good grasp of Django and Django Rest Framework(API development).
- ◆ Proficiency in HTML5, CSS3 and Tailwind CSS.
- Intermediate level knowledge of React library.
- Basic JavaScript programming skills.
- Good command of Linux operating systems.
- ◆ Integrating Django with third party APIs like Stripe.
- ◆ Intermediate knowledge of Object Relational Mapping and custom managers.
- ◆ Good knowledge of relational databases like MySQL and PostgreSQL.

# **Interpersonal Skills**

- Excellent communication.
- ◆ Excellent problem solving skills.
- Team player and collaborator.
- Quick learner and researcher.

### **Past Projects**

- ✓ <u>Comms-ltd</u> was a fiction company that sold internet bundles. The project was assigned by a client on Fiverr to create a system that allows customers to subscribe to internet plans. The project helped me to understand how to customize the default authentication system provided by Django and understand CRUD operations.
- ✓ <u>OCR APP</u> was my final year project. I created this application to solve a problem that most of my classmates were going through. The lecturer could send assignments as images but the students needed documents that they could copy and do research easily using AI tools. I deployed the PyTesseract algorithm into Django and created a form to allow editing of PDFs generated from images.
- ✓ <u>Ecommerce</u> (ShoeSoko) was a shoe retail marketplace project with Stripe API integration to allow customers to pay using credit cards. The project allowed me to learn how to configure asynchronous actions using Celery and RabbitMQ message broker, creating a cart and storing it within a request object and many more.
- ✓ <u>YourPortfolio</u> was a project that allowed me to share my portfolio template to other developers. If a developer likes my portfolio design, he can create an account on the website and upload details which will be then rendered as their own portfolio, saving developers the need to buy domain names and the tedious work of designing their own portfolio websites.
- ✓ <u>MyBlog</u> is a blogging website that allows internet surfers to create blogs or read others' while commenting on them. While making the code-base, I learn't SEO optimization techniques such as making canonical URLs for objects, creating sitemaps to improve search engine rankings and much more.

All codes are available on my *GitHub page*.

### **Education record**

- **Bachelor of Science (Bsc) Computer Science** (Laikipia University) 2019-2023.
- **High school certificate** (Kiamuchii secondary school) 2014-2018.

#### **Certifications**

- Google IT Support professional.
- Fundamentals of Python programming.

# **Work Experience**

✓ **Freelance work on Fiverr** (2020-present).

Documenting and refactoring python projects for clients.

Writing code in compliance with requirements provided by a client.

Creating databases using MySQL and using for Backend with Django.

✓ **Internship at Thika Level 5 Hospital** (May 2023 – September 2023)

Creating local backups to store important data for doctors and administrators.

Installing network devices and cables at various parts of the hospital where required.

Computer maintenance, repair and troubleshooting at the IT department.

Installation and configuration of drivers on various user terminals.

- **✓** Volunteer Full Stack Developer at Computer Engineering Forum (2023).
- **✓** Renovation of Lamwa Vetcare website (2023).

# **Languages**

English – Excellent

Swahili – Excellent

# **References**

**1.** Felex Onyango - Senior Software Engineer at Sibasi Ltd.

Contact: +254748793263

**2.** Lorna Ogake – Lecturer at Laikipia University.

Contact: +254714195873